原视频名：WHY Is Starship FLIGHT 5 Delayed？ ｜ Starbase Update
原作者名：NASASpaceflight
视频来源：youtu.be/elaiPXk4I3Y
原视频发布日期：20240916
字幕翻译：旋火
备注：视频仅截取后半部分
Okay now for the big news.
好了 现在来谈谈大新闻
and you better strap in because there's a lot of information here.
你最好注意看 因为这里的信息量很大
According to the FAA and SpaceX
根据美国联邦航空管理局(后简称FAA)和SpaceX的消息
Flight 5 is being delayed to no earlier than the end of November
第五次试飞会被推迟到不早于今年11月底
due to some environmental issues that have popped up.
推迟的原因是一些环境问题
This saga over the last week has a ton of angles
在过去的一周里 这一连串的事件有很多角度可以解读
so we're going to go through them step by step
所以我们将一步步地进行分析
and also talk about what SpaceX might be able to do in the interim.
并谈谈SpaceX在此期间可能做的事情
First off on Tuesday of this past week
首先是上周二
文章URL https://web.archive.org/web/20240911100837/https://www.spacex.com/updates/
SpaceX posted an update titled Starships are meant to fly
SpaceX发布了一篇题为 星际飞船就是要飞 的新闻
and it starts off talking about SpaceX as a company
而这篇文章一开始就谈到了SpaceX这家公司
as well as why they're making Starship in the first place.
以及他们为什么要制造星际飞船(后简称星船)
And I know we've all heard the phrase, Making Life Multiplanetary, more times than we can count.
我知道 我们都听过 让生命多行星化 这句话 而且听过的次数多得数不清
The update then goes on
这篇文章接着说
to talk about just how much progress SpaceX has made since starting the Starship program
SpaceX自启动星船项目以来取得了多大进展
and how they'll need to rapidly iterate
以及他们需要如何快速迭代
in order to fulfill their contract with NASA and the Artemis program
这样才能履行NASA和阿耳忒弥斯计划的合同
to get back to the moon and eventually Mars.
返回月球并最终到达火星
SpaceX mentions that it takes takes longer to do the paperwork than build the hardware
SpaceX提到文书工作的时间比设备制造的时间更长
which kind of doesn't make any sense
这有点说不通
平均每艘飞船或者助推器从建造到试飞成功需要大概一年的时间，
更不用说每一代设计的迭代花了多少时间
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SpaceX_Starship_(spacecraft), https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SpaceX_Super_Heavy
as it takes at least a year to get a Ship or Booster ready.
因为至少需要一年的时间才能准备好飞船或助推器
And this is just the delay of about 60 days or so.
而这仅仅是60天左右的延迟
We'll get to that 60 days number in just a second cuz there's a lot to unpack here.
我们等下就会提到60天这个数字 因为这里有很多东西需要解读
Now as SpaceX posted several weeks ago, the Flight 5 vehicles are ready to fly and that appears correct.
几周前SpaceX说第五次试飞载具准备就绪 现在看来是正确的
关于桑切斯厂区 https://starship-spacex.fandom.com/wiki/Sanchez_Site
Given that almost no work has been done to Ship 30 while sitting at the Sanchez a lot
鉴于30号飞船在桑切斯停放期间几乎没有进行任何工作
and Booster 12 remains parked in Mega Bay 1 complete with its hot stage ring.
而12号助推器仍停放在1号巨型厂房并配有热分离环 完成了装配工作
Then we get to the bad news
然后是坏消息
where SpaceX mentions the late November estimate for the launch license provided to them by the FAA
SpaceX提到了FAA向他们提供发射许可证的预计日期 在11月下旬
and they state that this is not related to a safety issue
而且他们表示这与安全问题无关
but is in fact environmentally related.
事实上 是与环境有关
However SpaceX failed to mention that
但SpaceX没有提到
they themselves submitted new information to the FAA in mid August
他们自己在今年8月中旬(才)向FAA提交了新的信息
which widened the environmental impact area.
其中扩大了环境的影响范围
This is kind of like turning in your homework late
这就有点像迟交作业
and wondering why you didn't get a full grade or why the grade late.
并想知道为什么没有得到满分 或者为什么更晚得到评分
Now this was in a statement from the FAA provided to NSF after an inquiry
那么这是FAA在询问后向我们提供的一份声明
and that statement reads
内容是
SpaceX目前第四次试飞的许可证
也允许同一载具配置和任务剖面的多次飞行
SpaceX选择为其提议的星船第五次试飞同时修改这两项内容
这引发了更深入的审查
此外 SpaceX在8月中旬提交了新的信息
详细说明了第五次试飞的环境影响会比之前审查中的区域更大
这就要求FAA与其他机构进行磋商
在获得FAA的发射授权之前 SpaceX必须满足所有安全 环境和其他许可要求
星船第五次试飞的最终批准 预计不会在2024年11月底之前做出
Now there's even more to unpack here.
现在 还有更多的内容需要解读
The FAA is essentially saying to SpaceX
FAA基本上是在对SpaceX说
听着 你有发射许可证 现在就可以进行飞行
你只需使用与第四次试飞相同的任务剖面和载具配置
This should apply to Booster 12 and Ship 30.
这应该(也)适用于12号助推器和30号飞船
Instead SpaceX opted to try for a catch.
然而SpaceX却(选择了修改任务剖面) 要让这次试飞尝试进行捕获
Of course last week we just got done talking about
当然 上周我们刚刚讨论了
视频URL https://youtu.be/Dt2uho5n3ZA?t=773
why SpaceX made this decision to try for a catch now rather than later
为什么SpaceX决定现在就尝试捕获而不是晚些时候
but that decision was easier to justify
但这个决定只有在这种情况下更合理
when we thought SpaceX would be flying sometime in late September or early October
也就是SpaceX的试飞发生在9月底至10月初
and not late November maybe even December
而不是11月底甚至12月
and I hate to say it.
而且我不想这么说
I hate to be that guy but at this point maybe even 2025.
甚至我也不想做指出这一点的人 但现在看来 甚至可能推迟到2025年
In addition to the problems with the launch license
除了发射许可证的问题
there are also issues to fix with the launch pad itself.
发射台本身也有问题需要解决
SpaceX presumably still has more testing to be done with Booster 14.1
SpaceX预计还需要对14.1号助推器进行更多测试
once all the reinforcements that are currently being installed on the Chopsticks and Tower are completed.
在目前筷子和发射塔上所有加固设备安装完成后
So why doesn't SpaceX just fly Ship 30 and Booster 12 using the same profile as Flight 4.
那么SpaceX为什么不使用与第四次试飞相同的任务剖面来进行第五次试飞呢
Well you'll have to ask them.
那么这得问他们
But SpaceX did ask the FAA for a multi-launch license and they got one.
但SpaceX确实向FAA申请了多次发射许可证 而且他们也拿到了
They just don't appear to want to use it now
只是他们现在似乎不想用了
which if I'm honest is a little bit frustrating.
说实话 这让我有点沮丧
I know we all want to see Starships fly and SpaceX could fly right now
我知道我们都想看到星船飞起来 而SpaceX现在就可以进行试飞
and just try for a catch later
然后在这次试飞之后 再尝试进行筷子捕获
once all of the issues with the pad and the Chopsticks are worked out.
同时发射场和筷子的问题也(有时间)得到解决
Later on in the update, SpaceX mentions that before Flight 4
在这条新闻的后面 SpaceX提到在第四次试飞之前
they looked at how the hot stage ring would fall to Earth
他们研究了热分离环坠落地球的问题
and where it would land and if it could have any impact on marine animal life.
以及坠落的地点 是否会对海洋生物造成影响
It worked in concert with the FAA and the National Marine Fisheries Service to determine those impacts.
SpaceX与FAA和美国国家海洋渔业局(后简称NMFS)合作确定了这些影响
According to SpaceX it was found that the impact was near zero.
根据SpaceX的说法 影响几乎为零
However that data seems to have changed after Starship Flight 4
然而 在第四次试飞之后 这一数据似乎发生了变化
once SpaceX got to see how the hot stage ring behaved in the real world.
此时SpaceX看到了热分离环在真实世界中的表现
After submitting this data in mid-August
在8月中旬这些数据提交之后
which according to SpaceX is a marginal change in Splashdown location
根据SpaceX的说法 这只是其溅落位置的微小变化
the FAA approved a 60-day consultation with the National Marine Fisheries Service
FAA批准与NMFS进行为期60天的磋商
to determine if there were any new significant impacts.
以确定是否有任何新的重大影响
I guess at least the question I have about all of this is
我想至少我对这一切的疑问是
how much bigger is the Hazard Area
危险区域有多大
or how much different is the hot stage ring location that this sort of review was necessitated.
或者说 热分离环的溅落区域有多大的不同才需要进行这样的审查？
All right now we get to get into the really fun side of the environmental issues at play here
现在 我们将进入环境问题真正有趣的一面
and those are the fines that SpaceX has had to pay
那就是SpaceX不得不支付的罚款
with regards to its deluge system that was built after Flight 1.
这些罚款与首次试飞后建设的喷水系统有关
First off the Texas Commission on Environmental Quality or TCEQ
星船试飞发生在德克萨斯州
首先 德克萨斯州环境质量委员会(后简称TCEQ)
had fined SpaceX for not having the correct permit to operate their deluge system.
对SpaceX进行了罚款 原因是其喷水系统没有获得正确的运行许可
This was originally slated to be a $5,000 fine out of a maximum of $25,000
这原本是最高25000美元罚款中的5000美元
but it was knocked down to $3,750
但被降到了3750美元
due to the fact that SpaceX had recently applied for an individual TPDES
因为SpaceX最近(2024年7月1日)申请了单独的TPDES
or Texas Pollutant Discharge Elimination System, Industrial Wastewater Permit on July 1st 2024.
全称是德州污染物排放移除系统 工业废水许可证
Yeah that's a mouthful.
是啊 这真拗口
This deluge has been operating since July 17th 2023 when it was first used after being built
这套喷水系统从2023年7月17日开始运行
because of course Flight 1 dug a massive hole in the ground.
当然 喷水系统的建设是因为首次试飞在地面上挖了一个大坑
In their update SpaceX said that this deluge fell under the Texas Multi-Sector General Permit.
SpaceX在新闻中表示 该喷水系统处在德州多部门通用许可范围内
I'm no environmental expert
我不是环境专家
but apparently this was not the appropriate permit for it to be classed under.
但很显然 这并不属于该通用许可的范围内
Now to be fair SpaceX does say they have a permit number assigned
说句公道话 SpaceX确实说他们有一个许可证编号
which became active in July of 2023
而该许可证于2023年7月生效
which is of course when the delug system was first activated.
当然 这也是喷水系统首次启动的时间
However SpaceX hasn't supplied that permit number
然而SpaceX并未提供该许可证编号
nor any sources that the TCEQ signed off on the deluge.
也没有任何消息来源证明TCEQ许可了喷水系统
It's only their words so it's a bit of an open question of who told who what and when.
这只是他们的一面之词 这到底怎么回事还不清楚
As we read on, SpaceX talks about how the deluge system uses literal drinking water
我们接着读这篇文章 SpaceX说喷水系统使用的是真正的饮用水
and those are their words not ours
这是他们说的 不是我们说的
and while they may put drinking water into the tanks
虽然他们可能会把饮用水放进水箱里
there is no way that the water coming out is drinkable afterwards
但之后流出的水是不可饮用的
unless SpaceX went through all the trouble of certifying the system as a potable water system.
除非SpaceX费尽周折将该系统认证为饮用水系统
Would you want to drink the water that's coming out of the deluge plate
你会想喝从喷水板中流出的水吗
especially after it's hit with Raptor engine exhaust?
特别是在被猛禽发动机排出的废气碰撞之后
I mean I probably would
我是说我可能会想试试
but something I would do is not exactly a measure of a good idea.
但你不能拿我想做的事作为好坏的衡量标准
Anyway along with the fine from the TCEQ
总之 除了TCEQ的罚款之外
the EPA or Environmental Protection Agency also finds SpaceX for violations of the Clean Water Act
美国环保局(后简称EPA)还认定SpaceX违反了 清洁水法案
for not having the correct permit which we just talked about.
违反的原因是我们刚才提到的许可证问题
This fine is a little bit bigger but nothing that would actually hurt SpaceX.
这笔罚款数额稍大 但不会对SpaceX造成实际伤害
It's $143,378.
罚款金额143378美元
This is covering 8 discharges.
这涉及到8次排放
7 of which are from the water deluge system
其中7次来自喷水系统
and one of which was the discharge of 36,000 gallons of liquid oxygen into the wetlands.
其中一次是向湿地排放了136.3立方米的液氧
The water discharges are all from static fires, launches or just tests of the deluge system
污水的排放均来自静态点火 星船试飞或喷水系统测试
in which about 180,000 gallons of water were used.
其中使用了约681.4吨的水
An estimated 75,000 gallons of water were not captured or vaporized by rocket exhaust.
估计有283.9吨的水没有被火箭废气捕获或蒸发
And on average about 37,000 gallons of water went into the wetlands.
平均有约140.1吨的水流入湿地
Now I know what some of you are thinking
那么我知道你们有些人在想
that this is nothing compared to the amount of rainfall the area can get
与该地区的降雨量相比 这根本不算什么
but that rainfall does not go through an industrial process before being discharged into the wetlands.
但这些排入湿地的雨水不是工业废水
The liquid oxygen discharge however
然而 液氧排放
was shortly after Booster 7's spin prime mishap or spin boom or whatever you want to call it.
是在7号助推器的涡轮泵事故后不久发生的
Either way RIP white hose.
不管怎么说 安息吧 白色软管
After this mishap
事故发生后
SpaceX used the dump valves at the bottom of the Booster to drain the LOX from the vehicle.
SpaceX使用助推器底部的减压阀门将液氧从载具中排出
SpaceX ended up settling with the TCEQ and have a proposed administrative penalty with the EPA
SpaceX最终支付了TCEQ和EPA的行政罚款
公示URL https://www.epa.gov/tx/proposed-administrative-penalty-order-against-space-explorations-technologies-corp-spacex-clean
with a public comment period that closes on October 21st 2024.
该罚款的公众评议期将于2024年10月21日结束
And still questions remain.
然而问题依然存在
Did SpaceX really not know that that their deluge was not covered under the general permit?
SpaceX真的不知道他们的喷水系统不在通用许可范围内吗
Did the TCEQ really not tell them?
TCEQ真的没有告诉他们吗
Did the EPA not say anything?
EPA也没有说什么吗
Based on the finds it does seem like the TCEQ never signed off on the deluge.
根据目前的情况来看 TCEQ似乎从来没有签署过喷水系统的使用许可
Either way there's so many open questions
无论如何 都有很多问题悬而未决
and without SpaceX providing any source documents in their update
在SpaceX的新闻没有提供任何源文件的情况下
it makes it kind of hard to know exactly what's going on.
就很难知道到底发生了什么
Hopefully we'll get some more information at some point to determine what actually happened.
希望我们能得到更多信息 以确定到底发生了什么
But for now we can only use the information that we have at hand.
但现在 我们只能利用手头的信息来分析
Okay so after going through that super fun walk through,
好了 在经历了这个超级有趣的重述之后
let's go back to the launch license and Flight 5 as a whole.
让我们回到发射许可和第五次试飞的问题上来
SpaceX should be able to launch Ship 30 and Booster 12.
SpaceX应该能够发射30号飞船和12号助推器
Heck they should even be able to launch Ship 31 in Booster 13.
他们甚至可以用13号助推器发射31号飞船
I mean they have a multi-vehicle launch license for Block 1 Vehicles. Do they not?
我的意思是 他们有Block 1型星船的多次发射许可证 对吧
So why not use it?
那为什么不用呢
At this point it does sort of seem like SpaceX is their own worst enemy here
在这一点上SpaceX似乎是自相矛盾了
and it should be mentioned that
而且值得一提的是
SpaceX did in fact choose this particular licensing option
事实上SpaceX确实选择了这种特殊的许可方式
as it would be easier for them to iterate launch by launch.
因为这样更便于他们在发射中迭代(研发)
许可URL https://www.faa.gov/space/licenses/operator_licenses_permits
However the part 450 license is not designed for constant iteration
然而 第450条许可并不是为不断迭代而设计的
like what's being done with Starship.
并不是为星船设计的
It was instead designed as an all-encompassing license to cover launches and re-entry.
相反 它被设计成一个范围很大的许可证 涵盖发射和再入
Again there are so many layers to the story here and so many moving parts
同样 这里的故事有很多层次 有很多不同的东西
it's hard to know exactly who's right and who's wrong.
很难确定谁对谁错
As always we all want to see Starships fly
一如既往 我们都希望看到星船飞起来
and we all can't wait for Flight 5 to happen.
而我们都迫不及待地想看到第五次试飞
So hopefully things get sorted out sooner rather than later.
所以希望事情能尽早解决
I know this was a lot of talk about bureaucratic stuff
我知道这些都是官僚主义的东西
but it's important that we go over what's happening with Starship behind the scenes on the regulatory side.
但重要的是 我们要了解星船 在幕后监管方面的情况
All right that's it for this week.
好了 本周的节目到此结束
Thank you so much for watching.
感谢您的收看
Stay tuned.
敬请期待
We're going to go live when Ship 31 eventually does static fire whenever that happens.
当31号船最终静态点火的时候 我们将进行现场直播
Thank you for watching and as always don't forget be excellent to each other.
感谢您的收看 也请大家互相保持友善
Also Dan's here.
Dan也来了
Also Dan's helping us clean up after Hurricane Francine thrashed Starbase.
飓风弗朗辛袭击星基后 Dan在帮我们清理现场
It's a mess.
真是一团糟